You mentioned that when the activity implements the LoaderCallback method
你之前提到过 当 Activity 在 CreateLoader 上执行
onCreateLoader, we need to create and return a loader.
LoaderCallback 方法时 我们需要创建并返回一个 Loader
So how do we do that?
我们应该怎么做呢?
Well, to create a loader, we're going to subclass the AsyncTaskLoader class.
嗯 先创建一个 Loader 然后把 AsyncTaskLoader 类做为子类
The AsyncTaskLoader has all the benefits of a loader,
AsyncTaskLoader 有着 Loader 的所有优势
say in terms of being managed by the loader manager.
就是说 它可以被 LoaderManager 管理
And behind the scenes, it's actually using an AsyncTask to do the work.
实际上 在场景的背后 所有的作业 是通过 AsyncTask 来完成的
Now we interact with the AsyncTaskLoader just like any other loader.
现在我们来了解一下 AsyncTaskLoader 其实和其他 Loader 没有什么不同
Notice that the AsyncTaskLoader inherits behavior from the loader class.
请注意 AsyncTaskLoader 从 Loader 类继承行为
It's also generic class with the generic parameter D.
因此它也是一个带有 泛型参数 D 的泛型类
Scrolling down to the public methods section, we see that the parameter D is
向下滑动到公用方法部分 我们可以看到 泛型参数 D
being used as the return value of the loadInBackground method.
被用作 doInBackground 方法的返回值
This method is also abstract, meaning we need to define the behavior and
这个方法也是抽象的 就是说 我们需要定义行为
we need to return a value with any data type of our choosing.
并用我们所选的 数据类型来返回值
As long as the class declaration specifies what that data type
只要类的声明 已经预指定了
it is upfront.
数据类型
I think a concrete example will help you clarify and
我这里有一个具体的实例 这能够帮助你理解这个问题
combine all these things that we just covered.
并将我们刚刚讲的内容 联系起来
But this tutorial is a little old as you can tell from the UI, but
从 UI 上你可以看出 这个例子稍微有些旧了
I like the simplicity of this code.
但我喜欢这段简洁的代码
The goal of this code is to show a list of employees in a ListView
这个代码的目的是要在 ListView 中显示一个雇员列表
by loading the data from a background thread within AsyncTaskLoader.
而这将通过从 AsyncTaskLoader 内的 后台线程加载数据来完成
The webpage is linked below if you want to check it out later.
如果你想要在以后访问 下面的链接
Let's look at the EmployeeLoader class.
下面让我们来看一下 EmployeeLoader 类
As you can see we extend from the AsyncTaskLoader class.
如你所见 这个是 AsyncTaskLoader 类的扩展
For the generic parameter in brackets, we specify a list of employees.
对于尖角号中的泛型参数 我们把它指定为一个雇员列表
That means that the return value of the loadInBackground method
这意味着 doInBackground 方法的返回值
is a list of employees.
就是雇员列表
Okay, so within the loadInBackground method,
好的 在 loadInBackground 方法内
we see that a new array list of employees is created.
我们能够看到一个 新创建的雇员数组列表
We add three entries to the list and then we return the list.
我们在列表中添加三个项 然后我们返回这个列表
Now technically,
从技术层面来说
the work being done in this method can be done on the main thread.
作业在此方法上完成的同时 也在主线程上完成了
Because it isn't an expensive calculation or say a network call.
毕竟这不是一个复杂的 计算或者网络调用
But the writer of this article just wanted a simple example to show
这篇代码的作者 仅仅是想要列举一个简单的例子
the AsyncTaskLoader class.
来说明 AsyncTaskLoader 类
We also have a constructor to create a new EmployeeLoader instance.
我们也有创建 新 EmployeeLoader 实例的构造函数
Inside, we just call the super class constructor and
在这里面 我们只是调用 超类构造函数
pass in the context and that's it.
并且浏览全文
See, a loader is pretty straightforward to implement.
可以看出 Loader 的执行 非常直接
Step back a little bit.
让我们回过头看一下
We could look at how the loader is being used in the context of the app.
Loader 在应用环境中 是如何使用的
Now in the activity class declaration,
在 Activity 类声明中
we can see that the MainActivity extends from the FragmentActivity.
我们能够看见 FragmentActivity 的扩展 MainActivity
And then implements the LoaderManager LoaderCallbacks interface.
然后执行一下 LoaderManager LoaderCallbacks 界面
The generic type specified is a list of employees.
雇员列表是 指定的泛型类型
Scrolling down, as you can see,
向下滑动页面 如你所见
that means the activity must implement the three abstract callback methods,
Activity 必须实行三个 抽取回调方法
onCreateLoader, onLoaderFinished and onLoaderReset.
onCreateLoader、onLoaderFinished 和 onLoaderReset
Now notice that the List Employee data type is used throughout the callback
那么让我们来注意一下 ListEmployee 数据类型被应用于整个回调
methods.
方法
Even though there's a lot of bracket symbols,
甚至这里还有很多 尖角号
just treat List Employee as a single blob.
仅将 ListEmployee 作为 一个独立的 BLOB 来使用
That same blob is inserted in different spots throughout the callback method
相同的 BLOB 被插入到 整个回调方法说明的
signatures.
不同的点上
For example, in the onCreateLoader method, it returns a loader that loads
例如 在 onCreateLoader 方法中返回一个 在雇员列表中用于加载数据的 Loader
data in the form of a list of employees, the same blob we used above.
与我们上面所用的 BLOB 使用方法相同
Now within the method, we create a new EmployeeLoader,
现在 我们在方法中创建了一个新的 EmployeeLoader
which extends from loader List Employee, so it matches the required return value.
其作为 loader ListEmployee 的扩展 与所需的返回值相匹配
Then we return the loader instance.
然后我们返回 Loader 实例
In the onLoadFinished method, we received two inputs.
在 onLoadFinished 方法中 我们得到两个输入参数
A loader and a result.
"Loader" 和“结果”
The result is of data type of List Employee and
“结果”是指 ListEmployee 的数据类型
the loader load List Employee data.
而 "Loader" 加载 ListEmployee 数据
Now the real value we care about is this result object.
现在我们真正关心的是 这个结果对象
We take the list of employees and update the data set in the adapter which
我们看一下雇员列表 并更新一下适配器中的数据集
will update the list view that it's tied to.
这将同时更新 与之相连的 ListView
In the onLoadReset method, we receive one input, the loader itself.
在 onLoadReset 方法中 我们得到一个输入参数 即 Loader 本身
Now since we only have one loader in the activity,
因为我们在 Activity 上 只有一个 Loader
we can just clear out the previous data that the loader gave us last time.
我们只能清除上次 Loader 给我们的数据
So we set the adapter data set to be an empty list of employees.
所以我们把适配器数据集 设成一个空的雇员列表
Here's the full scenario.
这是一个完整的场景
Within our activity to kick off the loader in the first place,
在 Activity 内 不把 Loader 放在第一个位置上
we get the LoaderManager and had called an itLoader on it.
把 LoaderManager 和 itLoader 放在上面
By the way, getSupportLoaderManager is the same as getLoaderManager.
顺便说一下 getSupportLoaderManager 和 getLoaderManager 是一样的
But this version uses the support loader version of the LoaderManager.
但是这个版本使用 LoaderManager 的 SupportLoader 版本
Within the initLoader call, the manager first checks to see if that loader
在 initLoader 调用内 Manager 首先检查 Loader
has already been created and passes back the existing copy if so.
是否已经创建 以及现有副本是否回传
If a loader instance doesn't exist,
如果 Loader 实例不存在的话
the onCreateLoader callback is triggered to create a new instance.
onCreateLoader 回调将被触发 来创建新的实例
Then we can create a new EmployeeLoader instance and return it.
然后我们就能够创建一个新的 EmployeeLoader 实例并返回
Here's the full scenario, within our activity to kick off a loader in
这是一个完整的场景 在 Activity 内 不把 Loader 放在第一个位置上
the first place, we get the LoaderManager and call initLoader on it.
我们获得 LoaderManager 并调用其上的 itLoader
By the way, getSupportLoaderManager is the same as getLoaderManager.
顺便说一下 getSupportLoaderManager 和 getLoaderManager 是一样的
But this version uses the support loader version of the LoaderManager.
但是这个版本使用 LoaderManager 的 SupportLoader 版本
So within the initLoader call, the manager first checks to see if
在 initLoader 调用内 Manager 首先检查
that loader has already been created and passes back the existing copy if so.
Loader 是否已经创建 以及现有副本是否回传
If a loader instance doesn't exist,
如果 Loader 实例不存在的话
then the onCreateLoader callback is triggered to create a new instance.
然后 onCreateLoader 回调将被触发 来创建新的实例
Then we've created a new EmployeeLoader instance and return it.
然后我们就能够创建一个新的 EmployeeLoader 实例并返回
You notice that after we initialized the loader, the code calls forceLoad.
你也许已经注意到了 在 Loader 初始化之后 代码调用 ForceLoad
This is required to trigger the loader to start doing the background work.
这需要触发 Loader 来进行后台作业
It's good practice though to put the forceLoad call
这是一个非常好的练习 将 ForceLoad 调用放置在
within the loader subclass.
Loader 子类内
You override the onStartLoading method within the loader class and
你可以在 Loader 类内覆盖 onStartLoading 方法
then call forceLoad from there.
并从这里调用 ForceLoad
The oStartLoading method is triggered automatically from initLoader.
onStartLoading 方法将在 initLoader 中自动触发
Okay, once we call forceLoad, then the loader started.
那么 当我们调用 ForceLoad 时 Loader 将被启动
The loadInBackground method gets run on a background thread and
loadInBackground 方法 会在后台线程上运行
the list of employees is created and returned as the result of the loader.
雇员列表将被创建并 作为 Loader 的结果返回
Now once the loader has finished loading data, it'll inform the LoaderManager
现在只要 Loader 加载数据完毕 就会通知 LoaderManager
which then pass the data to the onLoadFinished method.
将数据传回 onLoadFinished 方法
When the onLloadFinished method is called with the list of employees.
当 onLoadFinished 方法和 雇员列表一起被调用时
Then we update the adapter with the new data, causing the list to update and
我们用新数据更新了适配器 这将导致列表被更新和
redraw.
重绘
When our activity's being shut down,
当 Activity 被关闭时
the LoaderManager will take care of destroying our loader.
LoaderManager 将 销毁 Loader
And will inform us when the data being provided by the loader
并在 Loader 提供的数据 失效时
is no longer valid.
进行通知
In which case, we should remove it from the UI and stop using it.
在这种情况下 我们应将它 从 UI 中移除并停止使用
If the activity is destroyed before a load is finished,
如果在加载完成之前 Activity 被销毁
then this method won't be called.
那么这个方法就不会被调用
If we ran this code on our device,
如果我们在设备上运行这个代码
the app would look something like this screenshot.
这个应用就会像 屏幕截图中显示的一样
I know, the UI looks a little dated.
我知道 这些 UI 看起来有点过时了
But mainly it's because the emulator in Android Studio has been updated quite
但这主要是因为 Android Studio 中的 模拟器在这个教程创建之后
a bit since this tutorial was created.
进行了很多更新
Now that we've come full circle on how the Loader and
现在我们将 Loader 和 Loader Manager 回调作业
the Loader Manager callbacks work.
连成了一个完整的知识链
Since we discussed how to implement the Loaders in this video,
那么让我们讨论一下如何 在这个视频内执行 Loader
I want you to attempt the following quiz by filling in the blanks.
我希望你能够试着 填写下列问题的空白处
What is the type of Loader that uses an AsyncTask to do the background work?
使用 AsyncTask 进行 后台作业的 Loader 类型是什么？
To create a custom Loader that fetches a list of Earthquake objects,
为了创建一个 获取地震对象列表的自定义 Loader
we can define an EarthquakeLoader class which extends from what?
我们可从什么中定义一个 EarthquakeLoader 类？
Within the EarthquakeLoader class, we need to override what method,
在 EarthquakeLoader 类内 我们需要覆盖何种方法？
which will run on the background thread and return a list of Earthquakes.
该方法会在后台线程上运行 并随后返回地震列表
Again, as a hint,
最后 作为提示
you can choose from the possible answer choices in the notes below the quiz.
你可以从测验下面的注释中 选择一个合适的答案